[
    {
        "question": "أَتَاكَ",
        "answer": "(there) come to you",
        "pcklId": "260",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "atāka",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " هَلْ أَتَاكَ حَدِيثُ مُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَآثَرَ",
        "answer": "And preferred",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 14,
        "tlit": "waāthara",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآثَرَ الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "أ ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آثَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to prefer",
        "waznTlit": "āthara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَخَذَهُ",
        "answer": "So seized him",
        "pcklId": "126",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "fa-akhadhahu",
        "frequency": "273",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَهُ اللَّهُ نَكَالَ الْآخِرَةِ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take, to seize",
        "waznTlit": "akhadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرَةِ",
        "answer": "(for) the last",
        "pcklId": "153",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirati",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَهُ اللَّهُ نَكَالَ الْآخِرَةِ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "236",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَادَاهُ رَبُّهُ بِالْوَادِ الْمُقَدَّسِ طُوًى",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَإِذَا",
        "answer": "What! When",
        "pcklId": "355",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "a-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا كُنَّا عِظَامًا نَخِرَةً",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "But when",
        "pcklId": "356",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الطَّامَّةُ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذًا",
        "answer": "then",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 28,
        "tlit": "idhan",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا تِلْكَ إِذًا كَرَّةٌ خَاسِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِذًا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِذًا",
        "waznEnglish": "then",
        "waznTlit": "idhan",
        "waznType": "Particle (Answer particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "And the earth",
        "pcklId": "451",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍa",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ دَحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "552",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ يَوْمَ يَرَوْنَهَا لَمْ يَلْبَثُوا إِلَّا عَشِيَّةً أَوْ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2825",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَهُ اللَّهُ نَكَالَ الْآخِرَةِ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "726",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " اذْهَبْ إِلَىٰ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّهُ طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "[to]",
        "pcklId": "727",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقُلْ هَلْ لَكَ إِلَىٰ أَنْ تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "728",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَهْدِيَكَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَتَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "To",
        "pcklId": "729",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ مُنْتَهَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمِ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "136",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "ami",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمِ السَّمَاءُ بَنَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْرًا",
        "answer": "(the) matter",
        "pcklId": "243",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amran",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُدَبِّرَاتِ أَمْرًا",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "Then as for",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "fa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "But as for",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَتَذَكَّرُ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "and the first",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "wal-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَهُ اللَّهُ نَكَالَ الْآخِرَةِ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "(is) the refuge",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 87,
        "tlit": "l-mawā",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّ الْجَحِيمَ هِيَ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَأْوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "I will betake myself",
        "waznTlit": "mawā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "the refuge",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 87,
        "tlit": "l-mawā",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّ الْجَنَّةَ هِيَ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَأْوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "I will betake myself",
        "waznTlit": "mawā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآيَةَ",
        "answer": "the sign",
        "pcklId": "379",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "l-āyata",
        "frequency": "382",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَاهُ الْآيَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبُرِّزَتِ",
        "answer": "And will be made manifest",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 115,
        "tlit": "waburrizati",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبُرِّزَتِ الْجَحِيمُ لِمَنْ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُرِّزَتِ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make manifest",
        "waznTlit": "burrizati",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْصَارُهَا",
        "answer": "Their eyes",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "abṣāruhā",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَبْصَارُهَا خَاشِعَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْدَ",
        "answer": "after",
        "pcklId": "207",
        "rootWordId": 139,
        "tlit": "baʿda",
        "frequency": "235",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ دَحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ب ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْد",
        "waznEnglish": "was long",
        "waznTlit": "baʿd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَنَاهَا",
        "answer": "He constructed it",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "banāhā",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمِ السَّمَاءُ بَنَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to construct, to build",
        "waznTlit": "banā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَتْبَعُهَا",
        "answer": "Follows it",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "tatbaʿuhā",
        "frequency": "172",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَتْبَعُهَا الرَّادِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَبِعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "tabiʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْجِبَالَ",
        "answer": "And the mountains",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "wal-jibāla",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجِبَالَ أَرْسَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمُ",
        "answer": "the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmu",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبُرِّزَتِ الْجَحِيمُ لِمَنْ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمَ",
        "answer": "the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīma",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّ الْجَحِيمَ هِيَ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَنَّةَ",
        "answer": "Paradise ",
        "pcklId": "179",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "l-janata",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّ الْجَنَّةَ هِيَ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَتِ",
        "answer": "comes",
        "pcklId": "270",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāati",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الطَّامَّةُ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَدِيثُ",
        "answer": "(the) story",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 297,
        "tlit": "ḥadīthu",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " هَلْ أَتَاكَ حَدِيثُ مُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَدِيث",
        "waznEnglish": "Do you tell them",
        "waznTlit": "ḥadīth",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَحَشَرَ",
        "answer": "And he gathered",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 322,
        "tlit": "faḥashara",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَحَشَرَ فَنَادَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَشَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ḥashara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَافِرَةِ",
        "answer": "the former state",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 338,
        "tlit": "l-ḥāfirati",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُونَ أَإِنَّا لَمَرْدُودُونَ فِي الْحَافِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَافِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the former state",
        "waznTlit": "ḥāfirat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَيَاةَ",
        "answer": "the life",
        "pcklId": "169",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "l-ḥayata",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآثَرَ الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَيَوٰة",
        "waznEnglish": "you will live",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَخْرَجَ",
        "answer": "and brought out",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "wa-akhraja",
        "frequency": "182",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَغْطَشَ لَيْلَهَا وَأَخْرَجَ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bring forth, to drive out",
        "waznTlit": "akhraja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَخْرَجَ",
        "answer": "He brought forth",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "akhraja",
        "frequency": "182",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَخْرَجَ مِنْهَا مَاءَهَا وَمَرْعَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bring forth, to drive out",
        "waznTlit": "akhraja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَاسِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "losing",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 406,
        "tlit": "khāsiratun",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا تِلْكَ إِذًا كَرَّةٌ خَاسِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاسِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "he (has) lost ",
        "waznTlit": "khāsirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَاشِعَةٌ",
        "answer": "humbled",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 409,
        "tlit": "khāshiʿatun",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَبْصَارُهَا خَاشِعَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاشِع",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will be) humbled",
        "waznTlit": "khāshiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَخْشَىٰ",
        "answer": "so you would fear",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 410,
        "tlit": "fatakhshā",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَهْدِيَكَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَتَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَشِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear",
        "waznTlit": "khashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْشَىٰ",
        "answer": "fears",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 410,
        "tlit": "yakhshā",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَعِبْرَةً لِمَنْ يَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَشِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear",
        "waznTlit": "khashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْشَاهَا",
        "answer": "fears it",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 410,
        "tlit": "yakhshāhā",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّمَا أَنْتَ مُنْذِرُ مَنْ يَخْشَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَشِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear",
        "waznTlit": "khashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلْقًا",
        "answer": "creation",
        "pcklId": "243",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalqan",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمِ السَّمَاءُ بَنَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلْق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khalq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَافَ",
        "answer": "feared",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 444,
        "tlit": "khāfa",
        "frequency": "124",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ و ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَافَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear, to be afraid",
        "waznTlit": "khāfa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "answer": "he turned his back",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "adbara",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَدْبَرَ يَسْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away, to depart",
        "waznTlit": "adbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْمُدَبِّرَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who arrange",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "fal-mudabirāti",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُدَبِّرَاتِ أَمْرًا",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُدَبِّرَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "disposing",
        "waznTlit": "mudabbirāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دَحَاهَا",
        "answer": "He spread it",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 459,
        "tlit": "daḥāhā",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ دَحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "د ح و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د ح و",
        "waznEnglish": "to spread",
        "waznTlit": "dāl ḥā wāw",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدُّنْيَا",
        "answer": "(of) the world",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 488,
        "tlit": "l-dun'yā",
        "frequency": "133",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآثَرَ الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "د ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُّنْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to draw",
        "waznTlit": "dun'yā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَذَكَّرُ",
        "answer": "will remember",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "yatadhakkaru",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَتَذَكَّرُ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to receive admonition",
        "waznTlit": "tadhakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرَاهَا",
        "answer": "(to) mention it",
        "pcklId": "192",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'rāhā",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فِيمَ أَنْتَ مِنْ ذِكْرَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اذْهَبْ",
        "answer": "Go",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 516,
        "tlit": "idh'hab",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " اذْهَبْ إِلَىٰ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّهُ طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَهَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go, to take away",
        "waznTlit": "dhahaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَرَاهُ",
        "answer": "Then he showed him",
        "pcklId": "252",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "fa-arāhu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَاهُ الْآيَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَىٰ",
        "answer": "sees",
        "pcklId": "253",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yarā",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبُرِّزَتِ الْجَحِيمُ لِمَنْ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَوْنَهَا",
        "answer": "they see it",
        "pcklId": "254",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yarawnahā",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ يَوْمَ يَرَوْنَهَا لَمْ يَلْبَثُوا إِلَّا عَشِيَّةً أَوْ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّهُ",
        "answer": "his Lord",
        "pcklId": "930",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbuhu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَادَاهُ رَبُّهُ بِالْوَادِ الْمُقَدَّسِ طُوًى",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "931",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَهْدِيَكَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَتَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّكُمُ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "932",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbukumu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ أَنَا رَبُّكُمُ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "(before) his Lord",
        "pcklId": "933",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "934",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ مُنْتَهَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْجُفُ",
        "answer": "will quake",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 537,
        "tlit": "tarjufu",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَرْجُفُ الرَّاجِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرْجُفُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to quake",
        "waznTlit": "tarjufu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّاجِفَةُ",
        "answer": "the quaking one",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 537,
        "tlit": "l-rājifatu",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَرْجُفُ الرَّاجِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّاجِفَة",
        "waznEnglish": "will quake",
        "waznTlit": "rājifat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَرْدُودُونَ",
        "answer": "indeed be returned",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 547,
        "tlit": "lamardūdūna",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُونَ أَإِنَّا لَمَرْدُودُونَ فِي الْحَافِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ر د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرْدُود",
        "waznEnglish": "they will be sent back",
        "waznTlit": "mardūd",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّادِفَةُ",
        "answer": "the subsequent",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 548,
        "tlit": "l-rādifatu",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " تَتْبَعُهَا الرَّادِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ر د ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّادِفَة",
        "waznEnglish": "close behind",
        "waznTlit": "rādifat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرْسَاهَا",
        "answer": "He made them firm",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 556,
        "tlit": "arsāhā",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجِبَالَ أَرْسَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر س و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "arsā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُرْسَاهَا",
        "answer": "(is) its arrival",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 556,
        "tlit": "mur'sāhā",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَسْأَلُونَكَ عَنِ السَّاعَةِ أَيَّانَ مُرْسَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر س و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُرْسَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "He made them firm",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sā",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَمَرْعَاهَا",
        "answer": "and its pasture",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 565,
        "tlit": "wamarʿāhā",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَخْرَجَ مِنْهَا مَاءَهَا وَمَرْعَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرْعَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and pasture",
        "waznTlit": "marʿā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَفَعَ",
        "answer": "He raised",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 573,
        "tlit": "rafaʿa",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَفَعَ سَمْكَهَا فَسَوَّاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَفَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to raise",
        "waznTlit": "rafaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "زَجْرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a shout",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 612,
        "tlit": "zajratun",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا هِيَ زَجْرَةٌ وَاحِدَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ز ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَجْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and he was repelled",
        "waznTlit": "zajrat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "answer": "purify yourself",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 624,
        "tlit": "tazakkā",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقُلْ هَلْ لَكَ إِلَىٰ أَنْ تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ك و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "tazakkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْأَلُونَكَ",
        "answer": "They ask you",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yasalūnaka",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَسْأَلُونَكَ عَنِ السَّاعَةِ أَيَّانَ مُرْسَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبْحًا",
        "answer": "swimming",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "sabḥan",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالسَّابِحَاتِ سَبْحًا",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبْح",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "sabḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالسَّابِحَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who glide",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "wal-sābiḥāti",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالسَّابِحَاتِ سَبْحًا",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَّٰبِحَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "sābiḥāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبْقًا",
        "answer": "(in) a race",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "sabqan",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالسَّابِقَاتِ سَبْقًا",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبْق",
        "waznEnglish": "has preceded you",
        "waznTlit": "sabq",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالسَّابِقَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who race each other",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "fal-sābiqāti",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالسَّابِقَاتِ سَبْقًا",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَّٰبِقَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "has preceded you",
        "waznTlit": "sābiqāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْعَىٰ",
        "answer": "striving",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "yasʿā",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَدْبَرَ يَسْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to strive, to run",
        "waznTlit": "saʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَعَىٰ",
        "answer": "he strove (for)",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "saʿā",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَتَذَكَّرُ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to strive, to run",
        "waznTlit": "saʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَمْكَهَا",
        "answer": "its ceiling",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 723,
        "tlit": "samkahā",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " رَفَعَ سَمْكَهَا فَسَوَّاهَا",
        "rootWord": "س م ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س م ك",
        "waznEnglish": "its ceiling",
        "waznTlit": "sīn mīm kāf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the heaven",
        "pcklId": "347",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمِ السَّمَاءُ بَنَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالسَّاهِرَةِ",
        "answer": "(will be) awakened",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 733,
        "tlit": "bil-sāhirati",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا هُمْ بِالسَّاهِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "س ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ه ر",
        "waznEnglish": "(will be) awakened",
        "waznTlit": "sīn hā rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاعَةِ",
        "answer": "the Hour",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 742,
        "tlit": "l-sāʿati",
        "frequency": "49",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَسْأَلُونَكَ عَنِ السَّاعَةِ أَيَّانَ مُرْسَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "س و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the Hour",
        "waznTlit": "sāʿat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَوَّاهَا",
        "answer": "and proportioned it",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "fasawwāhā",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " رَفَعَ سَمْكَهَا فَسَوَّاهَا",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fashion, to proportion",
        "waznTlit": "sawwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَشَدُّ",
        "answer": "a more difficult",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 762,
        "tlit": "ashaddu",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمِ السَّمَاءُ بَنَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ش د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَشَدّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and harden",
        "waznTlit": "ashadd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضُحَاهَا",
        "answer": "its brightness",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 882,
        "tlit": "ḍuḥāhā",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَغْطَشَ لَيْلَهَا وَأَخْرَجَ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ض ح و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضُحًى",
        "waznEnglish": "exposed to the sun's heat",
        "waznTlit": "ḍuḥan",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضُحَاهَا",
        "answer": "a morning thereof",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 882,
        "tlit": "ḍuḥāhā",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ يَوْمَ يَرَوْنَهَا لَمْ يَلْبَثُوا إِلَّا عَشِيَّةً أَوْ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ض ح و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضُحًى",
        "waznEnglish": "exposed to the sun's heat",
        "waznTlit": "ḍuḥan",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَغَىٰ",
        "answer": "(has) transgressed",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "ṭaghā",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " اذْهَبْ إِلَىٰ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّهُ طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَغَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to transgress, to overflow",
        "waznTlit": "ṭaghā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَغَىٰ",
        "answer": "transgressed",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "ṭaghā",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَغَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to transgress, to overflow",
        "waznTlit": "ṭaghā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الطَّامَّةُ",
        "answer": "the Overwhelming Calamity",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 926,
        "tlit": "l-ṭāmatu",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الطَّامَّةُ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ط م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ط م م",
        "waznEnglish": "the Overwhelming Calamity",
        "waznTlit": "ṭā mīm mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "طُوًى",
        "answer": "(of) Tuwa",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 935,
        "tlit": "ṭuwan",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَادَاهُ رَبُّهُ بِالْوَادِ الْمُقَدَّسِ طُوًى",
        "rootWord": "ط و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طُوًى",
        "waznEnglish": "We will fold",
        "waznTlit": "ṭuwan",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَعِبْرَةً",
        "answer": "surely (is) a lesson",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 949,
        "tlit": "laʿib'ratan",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَعِبْرَةً لِمَنْ يَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِبْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "interpret",
        "waznTlit": "ʿib'rat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَشِيَّةً",
        "answer": "an evening",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 991,
        "tlit": "ʿashiyyatan",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ يَوْمَ يَرَوْنَهَا لَمْ يَلْبَثُوا إِلَّا عَشِيَّةً أَوْ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ع ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَشِيَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "turns away",
        "waznTlit": "ʿashiyyat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعَصَىٰ",
        "answer": "and disobeyed",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 997,
        "tlit": "waʿaṣā",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَذَّبَ وَعَصَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ص ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَصَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to disobey",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaṣā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِظَامًا",
        "answer": "bones",
        "pcklId": "127",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "ʿiẓāman",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا كُنَّا عِظَامًا نَخِرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "the Most High",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "l-aʿlā",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ أَنَا رَبُّكُمُ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَرْقًا",
        "answer": "violently",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1057,
        "tlit": "gharqan",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّازِعَاتِ غَرْقًا",
        "rootWord": "غ ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَرْق",
        "waznEnglish": "and We drowned",
        "waznTlit": "gharq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَغْطَشَ",
        "answer": "And He darkened",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1069,
        "tlit": "wa-aghṭasha",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَغْطَشَ لَيْلَهَا وَأَخْرَجَ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "غ ط ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غ ط ش",
        "waznEnglish": "to darken",
        "waznTlit": "ghayn ṭā shīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُقَدَّسِ",
        "answer": "the sacred",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1182,
        "tlit": "l-muqadasi",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَادَاهُ رَبُّهُ بِالْوَادِ الْمُقَدَّسِ طُوًى",
        "rootWord": "ق د س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُقَدَّس",
        "waznEnglish": "and we sanctify",
        "waznTlit": "muqaddas",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُلُوبٌ",
        "answer": "Hearts",
        "pcklId": "155",
        "rootWordId": 1222,
        "tlit": "qulūbun",
        "frequency": "168",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلُوبٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ وَاجِفَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلْب",
        "waznEnglish": "you will be returned",
        "waznTlit": "qalb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "They say",
        "pcklId": "1601",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlūna",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُونَ أَإِنَّا لَمَرْدُودُونَ فِي الْحَافِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They say",
        "pcklId": "1602",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا تِلْكَ إِذًا كَرَّةٌ خَاسِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقُلْ",
        "answer": "And say",
        "pcklId": "1603",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqul",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقُلْ هَلْ لَكَ إِلَىٰ أَنْ تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَالَ",
        "answer": "Then he said",
        "pcklId": "1604",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ أَنَا رَبُّكُمُ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقَامَ",
        "answer": "standing",
        "pcklId": "582",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "maqāma",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقَام",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "maqām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the great",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kub'rā",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَاهُ الْآيَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُبْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kub'rā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the great",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kub'rā",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الطَّامَّةُ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُبْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kub'rā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَذَّبَ",
        "answer": "But he denied",
        "pcklId": "174",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "fakadhaba",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَذَّبَ وَعَصَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَرَّةٌ",
        "answer": "(would be) a return",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1265,
        "tlit": "karratun",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا تِلْكَ إِذًا كَرَّةٌ خَاسِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ر ر",
        "waznEnglish": "a return",
        "waznTlit": "kāf rā rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنَّا",
        "answer": "we are",
        "pcklId": "1344",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا كُنَّا عِظَامًا نَخِرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَلْبَثُوا",
        "answer": "they had remained",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1313,
        "tlit": "yalbathū",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ يَوْمَ يَرَوْنَهَا لَمْ يَلْبَثُوا إِلَّا عَشِيَّةً أَوْ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ل ب ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَبِثَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remain, to stay, to hesitate, to delay",
        "waznTlit": "labitha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْلَهَا",
        "answer": "its night",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "laylahā",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَغْطَشَ لَيْلَهَا وَأَخْرَجَ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَتَاعًا",
        "answer": "(As) a provision",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "matāʿan",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " مَتَاعًا لَكُمْ وَلِأَنْعَامِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَتَٰع",
        "waznEnglish": "[then] I will grant him enjoyment",
        "waznTlit": "matāʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَاءَهَا",
        "answer": "its water",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "māahā",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَخْرَجَ مِنْهَا مَاءَهَا وَمَرْعَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَخِرَةً",
        "answer": "decayed",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1451,
        "tlit": "nakhiratan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا كُنَّا عِظَامًا نَخِرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ن خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن خ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "decayed",
        "waznTlit": "nūn khā rā",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَادَاهُ",
        "answer": "called him",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "nādāhu",
        "frequency": "53",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَادَاهُ رَبُّهُ بِالْوَادِ الْمُقَدَّسِ طُوًى",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "nādā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَنَادَىٰ",
        "answer": "and called out",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "fanādā",
        "frequency": "53",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَحَشَرَ فَنَادَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "nādā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْذِرُ",
        "answer": "(are) a warner",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "mundhiru",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّمَا أَنْتَ مُنْذِرُ مَنْ يَخْشَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنذِر",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "mundhir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالنَّازِعَاتِ",
        "answer": "By those who extract",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1457,
        "tlit": "wal-nāziʿāti",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّازِعَاتِ غَرْقًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّٰزِعَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "and You take away",
        "waznTlit": "nāziʿāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَشْطًا",
        "answer": "gently",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1473,
        "tlit": "nashṭan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّاشِطَاتِ نَشْطًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَشْط",
        "waznEnglish": "gently",
        "waznTlit": "nashṭ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالنَّاشِطَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who draw out",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1473,
        "tlit": "wal-nāshiṭāti",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّاشِطَاتِ نَشْطًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّٰشِطَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "gently",
        "waznTlit": "nāshiṭāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلِأَنْعَامِكُمْ",
        "answer": "and for your cattle",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "wali-anʿāmikum",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مَتَاعًا لَكُمْ وَلِأَنْعَامِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّعَم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿam",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّفْسَ",
        "answer": "his soul",
        "pcklId": "288",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "l-nafsa",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَكَالَ",
        "answer": "(with) an exemplary punishment",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1521,
        "tlit": "nakāla",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَهُ اللَّهُ نَكَالَ الْآخِرَةِ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَكَٰل",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) shackles",
        "waznTlit": "nakāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَهَى",
        "answer": "and restrained",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "wanahā",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to forbid",
        "waznTlit": "nahā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْتَهَاهَا",
        "answer": "(is) its finality",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "muntahāhā",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ مُنْتَهَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنتَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and forbidding",
        "waznTlit": "muntahā",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَهْدِيَكَ",
        "answer": "And I will guide you",
        "pcklId": "140",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "wa-ahdiyaka",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَهْدِيَكَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَتَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْهَوَىٰ",
        "answer": "the vain desires",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "l-hawā",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَافَ مَقَامَ رَبِّهِ وَنَهَى النَّفْسَ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَوَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "desire",
        "waznTlit": "hawā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاجِفَةٌ",
        "answer": "will palpitate",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1590,
        "tlit": "wājifatun",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلُوبٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ وَاجِفَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَاجِفَة",
        "waznEnglish": "you made expedition",
        "waznTlit": "wājifat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاحِدَةٌ",
        "answer": "single",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "wāḥidatun",
        "frequency": "68",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا هِيَ زَجْرَةٌ وَاحِدَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰحِدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "wāḥidat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْوَادِ",
        "answer": "in the valley",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1599,
        "tlit": "bil-wādi",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَادَاهُ رَبُّهُ بِالْوَادِ الْمُقَدَّسِ طُوًى",
        "rootWord": "و د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَاد",
        "waznEnglish": "the valleys",
        "waznTlit": "wād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "396",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَرْجُفُ الرَّاجِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "397",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَتَذَكَّرُ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "398",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "79",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ يَوْمَ يَرَوْنَهَا لَمْ يَلْبَثُوا إِلَّا عَشِيَّةً أَوْ ضُحَاهَا",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    }
]